# Frank Liu

I am a Ph.D. Student at Arizona State University, advised by Robert Likamwa in the Meteor Studio. I am interested in enhancing human computer interaction experiences through mixed reality and machine learning, advancing education and encouraging overall health and wellness. I enjoy working on projects that incorporate my diverse skillset in signal processing, physical prototyping, machine learning and human-computer interaction.

PhD Candidate
Electrical, Computer &
Energy Engineering
Arizona State University
Tempe, AZ

Website

fwliu1.github.io

**Email** 

fwliu1@asu.edu

#### **EDUCATION**

PhD Computer Engineering, Arizona State University

2018 - Present Advisor: Robert Likamwa

BS Electrical Engineering, University of Washington

2014 - 2018 Advisor: Hanchuan Li, Shwetak Patel

Summer 2016 University of California, Berkeley

Courses taken: Python and Big Data, Biostatistics

#### **HONORS & AWARDS**

Dean's Fellowship, Arizona State University

- Awarded to top 4% of admitted graduate students with significant leadership and research capabilities Peter E. Crouch Excellence Fund, 2020-2021, Arizona State University

Ira A. Fulton Fellowship, 2019-2020, Arizona State University

Herbold Foundation Fellowship, 2019-2020, Arizona State University

Engineering Graduate Fellowship, 2019-2020, Arizona State University

Priscilla and Melvin Wilson Endowed Scholar, University of Washington Electrical Engineering Departmental Honors IEEE HKN Honors Society, University of Washington

- Scholastic achievement in the top 30% of graduating class

Husky Leadership Certificate, University of Washington

# PEER-REVIEWED PUBLICATIONS

P4 Coordinate: A spreadsheet-programmable augmented reality framework for immersive map-based visualizations

Aashiq Shaikh, Linda Nguyen, Alireza Bahremand, Hannah Bartolomea, **Frank Liu**, Van Nguyen, Derrick Anderson and Robert Likamwa.

Special Session Paper: International Conference on Artificial Intelligence & Virtual Reality (AIVR '19), San Diego, California

P3 SoberComm: Exploring the Feasibility of Facilitating Alcohol Dependent Patients to Improve Family Communication using Mobile Phones

Chuang-Wen You, Hung-Yeh Lin, Yaliang Chuang, Yi-Ching Huang, Jui-Ting Tsai, Shan Jean Wu, Chia-Hua Kuo, Ming-Chyi Huang, **Frank Wencheng Liu**, Jane Yung-Jen Hsu, Hui-Ching Wu.

ACM Interactive, Mobile, Wearable and Ubiquitous Technologies (IMWUT) September 2019

- P2 SWISH: A shifting-weight interface of simulated hydrodynamics for haptic perception of virtual fluid vessels Shahabedin Sagheb, **Frank Wencheng Liu**, Alireza Bahremand, Assegid Kidane, Robert Likamwa ACM UIST 2019, New Orleans, Louisiana
- P1 A Spatial Audio System for the Internet-of-Things

Frank Liu, Robert Likamwa

Demo: Hotmobile 2019, Santa Cruz, California Awarded: NSF Student Travel Grant

#### INTERNSHIP EXPERIENCE

Summer 2019 Clobotics, Bellevue, Washington

Computer Vision and Machine Learning Research Intern.

Shipped an end to end price tag decoding system for price and barcode reading for both android and GCP

Created and labeled US retail price tag dataset for training and testing

Summer 2018 National Taiwan University - IoX Center, Gongguan, Taiwan

Research Intern. Mentor: Professor Bing You

Award of Excellence: Significant contributions in shipping android application SoberComm, allows alcohol

dependent individuals and their family members to monitor alcohol usage

Spring 2018 Roxy Device, Seattle, Washington

Startup Intern.

Lead generation and public outreach for customer acquisition. Built, assembled, and QA tested Roxy Device

hardware systems.

Winter 2018 Microsoft, Redmond, Washington

Consultant.

Created labs, lessons and course content for the "Introduction to Device Programming" EDX (MICROSOFT COURSE) [DEV295X] using Microsoft's IOT Pack for Raspberry Pi for audience of thousand+ students

Spring 2017 Verizon Wireless, Bellevue, Washington

Systems Performance Intern.

Supported Systems Performance/Radio Frequency engineers in evaluating and improving areas of poor

coverage using internal SP / RF tools

### TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Arizona State Fall 2019: Teaching Assistant for AME 494, "Musical Microprocessors"

University Spring 2019: Teaching Assistant for AME 394, "Introduction to Mixed Reality"

University of Fall 2016, Spring 2017, Spring 2018: Grader and Teaching Assistant for EE215,

Washington "Introduction to Circuits"

Spring 2017, Classroom Instructor

Coding with Kids Taught coding course curriculum for scratch at local elementary schools.

#### **SERVICE**

Volunteer TEI 2019

Mentor Summer 2019, Advanced Robotics at the University of Washington

Summer 2019, Hacklodge Seattle

Member Fall 2017 – Spring 2018, The College of Engineering Student Advisory Council

Interviewed students and faculty about mental health on campus and prepared a recommendation report

#### **INVITED TALKS**

Scholar-Donor Recognition 2018

From my exemplary leadership and service on campus, I was personally invited by Michael Bragg, Dean of the College of Engineering, as a speaker for the 2017-2018 Scholar-Donor Recognition Luncheon.

#### **LEADERSHIP**

TedXASU Organizing Team

Spring 2019

Event with 1000+ tickets sold. Advised the development for the TedxASU application on android and iOS. Assisted in speaker selection, providing insights to the rest of the organizing team. Served

in full capacity for event setup and takedown

Sunhacks Organizing Team

Fall 2018

Lead marketing campaigns selling out tickets for 300+ participants

Organized the largest hackathon in Phoenix Area; Sunhacks, ASU's 36-hour hackathon

Advanced Robotics at the University of Washington

Spring 2017 – Summer 2018

Annotated meetings and weekly sprints coordinating 90 members

Raised over 18,000 in funding through philanthropy efforts and sponsorships

Refiller Robot Lead; Designed and conducted CAD reviews; wrote embedded software (C, C++,

Arduino) for robot control systems

Summer 2018 Placed 3rd in International Regionals | Summer 2017 Placed 31st out of 241 at

International DJI Robomasters competition in Shenzhen, China

## SELECTED PRESS

Sunhacks State Press. Sunhacks provides an inclusive outlet for ASU students

Advanced Robotics at the University of Washington

UW Daily. Robotics team breaking down obstacles... literally

**Seattle Times**. These attack robots and their UW creators will take on the world at RoboMaster competition in China

**Seattle Times**. UW students and their attack robots hit bumps in China — then a hotel hair dryer saved the

Bloomberg. China's High-Stakes Robot Wars

# **REFERENCES**

Robert Likamwa likamwa@asu.edu

Shwetak Patel shwetak@cs.washington.edu